During Metal Gear Solid 4, we tested some simulation-based modeling tools, but it was difficult to use these tools for any high-res models that required baking normal maps.
However, when using Marvelous Designer on this project, it was very quick and easy to get high-quality cloth models.
In the final scene in the trailer, Snake's stitching on his shoulders was done completely in Marvelous Designer.
No one had to touch it up by hand, and it sure did turn out pretty well, we think.
And here's another demonstration of Marvelous Designer.
It is incredibly simple in Marvelous Designer to set up a specific pattern to get a high-quality result.
Just by setting a pattern and generating the model, the time saved for a modeler is limited.
It is enormous.
Here are some of the sleeves being adjusted.
And here are some wrinkles on his jacket being adjusted.
One big advantage is being able to adjust by hand the simulated result.
It is very useful.
Amazing...
Finally the polygon density is raised and recalculated.
The stitching near his shoulders turned out quite well.
You can see from this example.
Amazing...
Snake's goggles and gloves were both generated in the same way.
And here is the final result.
Next on the agenda is Mr. Suzuki to talk about Fox Engine shaders, lighting, and camera.